on today's video I want to show you how
you can use obsidian to get yourself a
second brain I use obsidian to take note
when I'm studying to brainstorm ideas
for YouTube videos to write the scripts
of the videos when I'm making a course
all the planning and research is done in
obsidian all the tasks and things I have
to do are written down in obsidian
obsidian
obsidian is not a normal note-taking app
it's a note taking app on steroids apart
from being free flexible and
customizable its killer feature is that
obsidian allows you to create links
between your notes obsidian generates a
knowledge grab that shows you the
connections and relationships between
Concepts and thoughts you can visualize
what you know it's like a brain map when
you know how one concept relates to
another concept you can learn remember
and understand more easily another cool
thing about obsidian is that it can be
used a hundred percent offline your
notes are stored locally on your
computer they are just file on a folder
that you can access at any time that
means that at any point you can share
your notes or move them to other apps
you are not locked in when you use
obsidian is the opposite of that after
you go to the website and download
obsidian which is available for iOS
Android Windows Mac and Linux you are
going to install obsidian and you're
going to be asked on which folder you
would like to create your first Vault an
obsidian vault is just a folder where
all the files you create inside of
obsidian will be saved after creating
the Vault obsidian will welcome you with
an empty screen showing you your empty
Vault on the sidebar we can tell that we
are inside of our vault but of course
there are no nodes on it yet to create a
new note we will press command and the
first line we write will be the title of
the note and will be set as the name of
the file obsidian supports markdown
which means we can use headers lists
links images YouTube video and Bets it
also has this cool concept of callouts
which are little alert you can create of
different kinds that can also be
foldable it also supports mermaid a
diagramming tool so we can insert
diagrams and charts inside of our notes
which is very useful when we are
learning new Concepts like I said before
the clear feature of obsidian is that it
allows us to create links between our
nodes using this feature we can organize
our knowledge better instead of putting
it all in one long file we can instead
write Atomic notes an atomic node should
have only one idea it should be
self-contained and understandable on its
own so let's pretend that we are
studying the data structures and
algorithms we will first create a file
with that name and then write an intro
of what data structures and algorithms
are in a list of some of them to create
a link to another note we are going to
wrap Stacks around two squared brackets
as you can see it is turned into a link
if I press command it says that that
node does not exist yet and that I have
to click to create it after command
click that will create a new stacks note
where we can write down what Stacks are
since we are mentioning cues on the Node
we should create a note about them again
we'll wrap the word cues around two
square brackets and press Ctrl or
command click then we write what cues
are and because we're mentioning slacks
let's create a link to it and now let's
go back to our main file and connect
cues to it as well now that we made all
the connections we can take a look at
the graph view by clicking the second
button on the left sidebar as you can
see we can now visualize how they are
all connected if we now go back to our
main file and create a link for hash
tables our graph view will start to grow
another cool thing about linking your
notes is that you can go to a note and
on the right sidebar you can see what
are the backlinks to it that means which
node is linking to that note another
obsidian feature that is sort of new is
are canvases which you can use to create
mind maps to create a canvas first we
open the common palette pressing command
P we select create new canvas and we
will get a canvas where we can now start
dragging positioning and connecting our
nodes we can also create cards and
connect our nodes to them we can edit
our notes right from the canvas and we
can also bring images files videos and
even websites to it I said before that
obsidian is very flexible and
customizable and that is because of its
awesome Community plugin system obsidian
plugins are built using JavaScript and
anyone can create one currently there
are more than 1 000 plugins which is a
number that is increasing day by day
there are plugins to add a calendar to
obsidian to create kanaban boards to
create slide presentations and much much
more my two favorite plugins are the
obsidian git plugin that backs up my
Vault into a private GitHub repository
and the tasks plugin let me show you how
that one works after enabling Community
plugins and installing the tasks plugin
on a file named to study the next time I
create a checkbox the plugin will kick
in and will allow me to set at view date
start date and schedule date it will
also let me set the priority level of
the task if let's say you have tasks in
two different files so for example if I
have a to study task list and a to-do
task list on another file called today I
can pull all the tasks that are for
example due today and that are not
completed yet by writing a query
provided by the plugin all I do is ask
for all the tasks that are not done in
that are due today and I group them by
filing now I can add tasks anywhere I
want and my today file will only give me
the tasks of the day also when I
complete a task from anywhere it will be
updated in both files I hope that today
you got a good overview of what obsidian
is and what makes it a special I hope
you liked the video and found it useful
if you did please like the video share
it with your friends and subscribe to
the channel obsidian has many cool
features and customization options you
can change colors install a different
theme create keyword shortcuts and more
so let me know in the comments if you
would like to see a video on also let me
know in the comments if you are already
an obsidian user and share with us what
are some cool plugins we can use to make
our second brain better and please don't
forget that if you want to learn to code
for free click the link below where you
can take free courses on JavaScript
python react react native go Dart
flutter and many others all for free
click the link below and I will see you
there
see you on the next one bye
oh